Her story made history
On the Basis of Sex is a drama, history film directed by Mimi Leder.
Young lawyer Ruth Bader Ginsburg teams with her husband Marty
to bring a groundbreaking case before the U.S.
Court of Appeals and overturn a century of sex discrimination.
Ruth Bader Ginsburg, played by Felicity Jones.
Martin D. Ginsburg, played by Armie Hammer.
Mel Wulf, played by Justin Theroux.
Erwin Griswold, played by Sam Waterston.
Dorothy Kenyon, played by Kathy Bates.
Jane C. Ginsburg, played by Cailee Spaeny.
On the Basis of Sex is a 2018 American biographical legal drama film based on the life and early cases of Ruth Bader
Ginsburg, who was the second woman to serve as an Associate Justice of the United States Supreme Court.
Directed by Mimi Leder and written by Daniel Stiepleman (Ginsburg's
real-life nephew), it stars Felicity Jones as Ginsburg.
Armie Hammer, Justin Theroux, Jack Reynor, Cailee Spaeny, Sam
Waterston, and Kathy Bates feature in supporting roles.
The film had its world premiere at the AFI Fest on November 8, 2018, and was theatrically
released in the United States on December 25, 2018, by Focus Features.
On the Basis of Sex received generally favorable reviews from critics, who praised
Jones' performance, the film's intricacy and its pacing at a dramatic level.
Other critics felt the biopic was predictable, over-packaged and hagiographic.
Made on a $20 million budget, On the Basis of Sex
grossed $38.8 million at the box office.
The film explores themes of 1970s, biography, based
on true story, supreme court, lawyer.
The tone is emotional.